

CONTACT

+55 21 99118-8759

in /pedro-paulo-weissenberg-2a38bb142



pedroweissenberg@gmail.com



/pweissenberg

NATIONALITIES AND LANGUAGES

I'm German and Brazilian. I speak both Portuguese and English fluently. I can also read and understand Spanish.

TECNOLOGY

I'm coding since I was 12. I can code on VBA, R, Python, SQL and M (PowerQuery). I have the Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate, IBM Data Science Professional Certificate, Datacamp Data Scientist Associate certificate, **Datacamp Data Analyst Associate** certificate, Machine Learning Specialization (Standford and Deepmind) certificate and Udemy's Machine Learning A-Z certificate.

PEDRO WEISSENBERG

ECONOMIST AND POLITICAL SCIENTIST

EDUCATION

IESP | Rio de Janeiro, RJ, Brazil (2021-2022)

Master of Political Science

Coursework: NLP, unsupervised learning, and sentiment analysis were applied to Brazilian deputies' speeches to identify how conservative the evangelical deputies were between 2006 and 2021.

PUC-Rio | Rio de Janeiro, RJ, Brazil (2019-2020)

Master of Economics

Coursework: Econometric models were applied to the USD/BRL exchange rate to determine if any could outperform a random walk in the long run.

Ibmec | Rio de Janeiro, RJ, Brazil (2014-2018)

Bachelor of Economics

Coursework: study about the Brazilian economy recess of 2014-2016.

EXPERIENCE

September 2023 - present

S&P Global – Commodities division: Data Modelling Analyst. I'm responsible for elaborate and maintain multiple models related to Natural Gas. For that, I daily use Python, VBA and SQL.

March 2023 - August 2023

Oliveira Trust: Controlling Analyst of Receivable Funds. I was responsible for funds' financial analysis and for process automatization. For that, I used to daily used Python, VBA and SQL.

December 2013 – February 2023

Other work experiences: Junior Researcher at NECON (Legislative Studies), assistant in the Political Economy class at IESP, intern at the Brazilian Statistical Institute (IBGE), intern at a law office, and math teacher at a local NGO.